A Guide to the Papers of the Twin Oaks Community,
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
- Series 1: Councils
  - J. Outreach Council
    - Outreach Council. Other Communities. Highlander Research and Education Center, 1984, 1 item. (Box-folder 15:4)
      One edition of Highlander Reports, the commune newsletter.
    - Outreach Council. Other Communities. Home in America, 1987, 1 item. (Box-folder 15:5)
      The first newsletter from the community.
    - Outreach Council. Other Communities. Institute for Social Ecology, 1986, 1 item. (Box-folder 15:6)
      The Institute for Social Ecology's pamphlet of 1986 program offerings.
    - Outreach Council. Other Communities. Jubilee, 1986-1988, 8 items. (Box-folder 15:7)
      Various publications for the community with multiple editions of the Jubilee Partners Report.
    - Outreach Council. Other Communities. Julian Woods, 1978, 1 item. (Box-folder 15:8)
      One document describing the beliefs and goals of the Julian Woods Community.
    - Outreach Council. Other Communities. Kerista, 1979-1987, 16 items. (Box-folder 15:9)
      Various newsletters about the non-monogamous community; flyers; informational publications.
    - Outreach Council. Other Communities. Koinonia Partners, 1978-1988, 33 items. (Box-folder 15:10)
      Newsletters; pamphlets; various other publications relating to the Christian commune.
    - Outreach Council. Other Communities. Kripalu Neighborood Technology, 1981; 1987-1988, 5 items. (Box-folder 15:11)
      Publications; program guides for the Yoga and rehabilitation center.
    - Outreach Council. Other Communities. Krutsio, 1984-1989, 11 items. (Box-folder 15:12)
      Newsletters; letters; photographs.
    - Outreach Council. Other Communities. Lama Foundation, 1979; 1984, 3 items. (Box-folder 15:13)
      Directory listing; newsletter; informational pamphlet for the commune.
    - Outreach Council. Other Communities. Los Horcones, 1979-1988, 9 items. (Box-folder 15:14)
      Letters to new members; flyers describing the commune.
    - Outreach Council. Other Communities. The Love Family, n.d., 1 item. (Box-folder 15:15)
      One newsletter publication by The Love Family.
    - Outreach Council. Other Communities. Mariposa School, 1986 March, 1 item. (Box-folder 15:16)
      One volume of the Mariposa School Newsletter.
    - Outreach Council. Other Communities. Matagiri (Sr. Aurobindo Center), 1978, 1 item. (Box-folder 15:17)
      One newsletter titled the Matagiri Collaboration for the Matagiri Sri Aurobindo Center.
    - Outreach Council. Other Communities. Mettanokit, 1985-1988, 4 items. (Box-folder 15:18)
      Letters; informational documents for The Mettanokit Community.
    - Outreach Council. Other Communities. Miccosukee Land, 1981;1985, 2 items. (Box-folder 15:19)
      One letter and one journal sent from the Miccosukee Land Co-op to Twin Oaks.
    - Outreach Council. Other Communities. Miscellaneous Community Photographs, n.d., 15 items. (Box-folder 15:20)
      Photographs from other communes and organizations.
    - Outreach Council. Other Communities. Moniteau Farm, 1981, 1 item. (Box-folder 15:21)
      Newsletter titled Spiral News from Moniteau Farm.
    - Outreach Council. Other Communities. Mt. Shasta, 1987, 1 item. (Box-folder 15:22)
      The Mount Shasta community newsletter sent to Twin Oaks.
    - Outreach Council. Other Communities. National Historic Communal Societies, 1976; 1983-1989, 26 items. (Box-folder 15:23)
      Newsletters; brochures from conferences; a bibliography of communes from Indiana State University's Special Collections.
    - Outreach Council. Other Communities. Neighborhood Caretaker, 1988, 4 items. (Box-folder 15:24)
      Four copies of the Neighborhood Caretaker, a Journal of Neighborhood Health Sciences.
    - Outreach Council. Other Communities. New Hope, 1979-1987, 9 items. (Box-folder 15:25)
      Newsletters and pamphlets about the emerging New Hope Community.
    - Outreach Council. Other Communities. New Land, 1987-1988, 5 items. (Box-folder 15:26)
      Community Newsletters and letters.
    - Outreach Council. Other Communities. New Vrindaban, 1980-1988; n.d., 7 items. (Box-folder 16:1)
      Letters and informational publications regarding the New Vrindaban Community.
    - Outreach Council. Other Communities. Our Land, 1984, 2 items. (Box-folder 16:2)
      Two letters pertaining to the Our Land Community.
    - Outreach Council. Other Communities. Padanaram, 1977-1986, 10 items. (Box-folder 16:3)
      Informational packets and flyers for the Padanaram community; newspaper article about Padanaram in ids from 3/22/79.
    - Outreach Council. Other Communities. Pendle Hill, 1988, 1 item. (Box-folder 16:4)
      Packet for the Resident Study Program at Pendle Hill.
    - Outreach Council. Other Communities. Philoxia, n.d., 2 items. (Box-folder 16:5)
      Two pamphlets advertising for the food and service available at Philoxia's Bed and Breakfast.
    - Outreach Council. Other Communities. Ponderosa Village, 1986; n.d., 7 items. (Box-folder 16:6)
      Informational flyers and leaflets for Ponderosa Village.
    - Outreach Council. Other Communities. Posehn's Community, 1985-1986, 5 items. (Box-folder 16:7)
      Letters and meeting minutes for Posehn's Community.
    - Outreach Council. Other Communities. Rainbow Network, 1977-1988, 21 items. (Box-folder 16:8)
      Photos and publications regarding festivals, program information, and newsletters.
    - Outreach Council. Other Communities. Renaissance Community, 1978; 1985, 3 items. (Box-folder 16:9)
      Newsletter and information about visits with the guest program of The Renaissance Community.
    - Outreach Council. Other Communities. Round Mountain, n.d., 1 item. (Box-folder 16:10)
      Information packet for the Round Mountain Cooperative Community.
    - Outreach Council. Other Communities. Sandhill, 1984-1987; 1995, 59 items. (Box-folder 16:11)
      One newsletter and many photographs of Sandhill.
    - Outreach Council. Other Communities. School of Living, 1974-1980; 1987, 4 items. (Box-folder 16:12)
      Documents about The School of Living and the Green Revolution.
    - Outreach Council. Other Communities. Seven Oaks, 1981-1985, 8 items. (Box-folder 16:13)
      Informational packets and flyers for Seven Oaks.
    - Outreach Council. Other Communities. Shannon Farm, 1978-1988, 7 items. (Box-folder 16:14)
      Newsletters, letters, and miscellaneous documents from the Shannon Community.
    - Outreach Council. Other Communities. Short Mountain, 1981-1988, 18 items. (Box-folder 16:15)
      Newsletters, informational packets, and miscellaneous documents for the commune.
    - Outreach Council. Other Communities. Sirius, 1982-1988, 5 items. (Box-folder 16:16)
      Newsletters and program packets for the Sirius Community.
    - Outreach Council. Other Communities. Springtree, 1976-1988, 11 items. (Box-folder 16:17)
      Five Springtree newsletters and six photographs of the community.
    - Outreach Council. Other Communities. Stelle, 1983-1988, 26 items. (Box-folder 16:18)
      Numerous publications of The Stelle Group Letter as well as other documents pertaining to the community. OS Map of Stelle.
    - Outreach Council. Other Communities. Trails End Community, 1986, 1 item. (Box-folder 16:19)
      One letter about starting a commune.
    - Outreach Council. Other Communities. The Ultimate Vehicle Family (The U.V. Family), 1980-1981, 2 items. (Box-folder 16:20)
      Newsletters for the Ultimate Vehicle Family.
    - Outreach Council. Other Communities. The Village of Oz, 1981, 1 item. (Box-folder 16:21)
      Village Oz pamphlet titled General Information and Calendar.
    - Outreach Council. Other Communities. Walden Farm, 1983; n.d., 3 items. (Box-folder 16:22)
      Documents concerning Walden Farm and the Circle of Angels.
    - Outreach Council. Other Communities. Yogaville, 1984-1989, 5 items. (Box-folder 17:1)
      Documents pertaining to various Yoga organizations and institutes.
    - Outreach Council. Other Communities. White Spruce Farm, n.d., 1 item. (Box-folder 17:2)
      Description of the Still Mountain Society Summer Program.
    - Outreach Council. Other Communities. Windstar, 1988, 2 items. (Box-folder 17:3)
      Two newsletters for Windstar.
    - Outreach Council. Other Communities. Womyn's Lands, 1983-1984, 2 items. (Box-folder 17:4)
      A letter and directory of land groups pertaining to lesbian communes.
    - Outreach Council. Other Communities. Yasodhara Ashram, 1988, 1 item. (Box-folder 17:5)
      A program list for the Yasodhara Ashram Yoga Retreat and Study Center.
    - Outreach Council. Other Communities. Zanies, 1977-1978, 2 items. (Box-folder 17:6)
      Two issues of the social newsletter.
  - Other International Communities
    - Outreach Council. Other International Communities. England (Centre for Alternative Technology), 1977, 1 item. (Box-folder 17:8)
      Large packet of information sheets about miscellaneous topics.
    - Outreach Council. Other International Communities. England (Laurieston Hall), 1987, 2 items. (Box-folder 17:9)
      Brochure and postcard.
    - Outreach Council. Other International Communities. England (Lifespan Community), 1984-1987, 11 items. (Box-folder 17:10)
      Information leaflets, weekly newsletter, etc.
    - Outreach Council. Other International Communities. England (Lightmoor), 1987-1988, 4 items. (Box-folder 17:11)
      Employment and educated related pamphlets.
    - Outreach Council. Other International Communities. England (Old Hall Community), 1974; 1989, 2 items. (Box-folder 17:12)
      A historical leaflet and a community guide.
    - Outreach Council. Other International Communities. England (The Teachers Community), 1981, 2 items. (Box-folder 17:13)
      Information pack and handbook.
    - Outreach Council. Other International Communities. European Community (Miscellaneous), 1979 - 1989, 4 items. (Box-folder 17:14)
      Documents related to communal living; The Collective Experience, which contains articles and poems about communal living.
    - Outreach Council. Other International Communities. Guatemala (Finca Jardin de Luz), 1985, 1 item. (Box-folder 17:15)
      Letter from Eddy Stylen to Egalitarian Communities about starting up a commune.
    - Outreach Council. Other International Communities. India (Auroville), 1958 - 1981; 1989, 20 items. (Box-folder 17:16)
      Articles and publications pertaining to communal living in India.
    - Outreach Council. Other International Communities. International Communes Network, 1980 - 1987, 5 items. (Box-folder 17:17)
      Documents related to the organization of the International Communes Network.
    - Outreach Council. Other International Communities. International Community Addresses, 1992-1993; n.d., 29 items. (Box-folder 17:18)
      Documents relating to communes across the world.
    - Outreach Council. Other International Communities. Ireland (Neve Shalom Community), 1986, 2 items. (Box-folder 17:19)
      Article on Northern Ireland and a copy of a support letter.
    - Outreach Council. Other International Communities. Israel (Diaspora Yeshiva Community), n.d., 1 item. (Box-folder 17:20)
      Letter from Rabbi Dr. Mordechai Goldstein to Twin Oaks regarding projects relating to Israel.
    - Outreach Council. Other International Communities. Israel (Kibbutz Aliya Desk and The Kibbutz Journal), 1980-1986, 11 items. (Box-folder 17:21)
      Publications of The Kibbutz Journal and related documents.
    - Outreach Council. Other International Communities. Israel (Kibbutz-related Bibliographies), 1980, 4 items. (Box-folder 17:22)
      Lists of publications relating to the Project for Kibbutz Studies.
    - Outreach Council. Other International Communities. Israel (Kibbutz Literary Digest Shdemot), 1976-1981, 5 items. (Box-folder 17:23)
      Four publications of the Literary Digest of the Kibbutz Movement and one subscription letter.
    - Outreach Council. Other International Communities. Israel (Kibbutzim Miscellaneous), 1954; 1971-1988; n.d., 57 items. (Box-folder 17:24)
      Letters, proposals, and miscellaneous documents pertaining to Kibbutzim and University study of Kibbutzim.
    - Outreach Council. Other International Communities.Israel (Kibbutz Scholarship), 1976-1980; n.d., 13 items. (Box-folder 18:1)
      Letters and documents pertaining to Israel and Kibbutz scholarships for Israelis.
    - Outreach Council. Other International Communities .Israel (Kibbutz Seminar Center of the Kibbutz Hameuchad Focus'son Publication), n.d., 10 items. (Box-folder 18:2)
      Articles on the Kibbutz lifestyle.
    - Outreach Council. Other International Communities. Israel (Kibbutz Studies Harvard University), 1976-1983, 10 items. (Box-folder 18:3)
      Documents related to the Harvard University Center for Jewish Studies.
    - Outreach Council. Other International Communities. Israel (Socialist Zionist Youth Movement), 1981, 2 items. (Box-folder 18:4)
      Two Youth and Nation publications titled Women in Israel and Jews Right and Left.
    - Outreach Council. Other International Communities. Israel (Yad-Tabenkin-EFAL Institute), 1979 - 1987, 21 items. (Box-folder 18:5)
      Bulletins of Yad-Tabenkin and pamplets with fact sheets.
    - Outreach Council. Other International Communities. Japan (Miscellaneous), n.d., 3 items. (Box-folder 18:6)
      A large publication titled The Modern Utopian about communes in Japan with two related leaflets.
    - Outreach Council. Other International Communities. New Zealand/Australia (Miscellaneous), 1974-1976; 1985, 4 items. (Box-folder 18:7)
      Publications about the Riverside commune, the Ohu commune, the Wyuna Community, and the Tui Land Trust.
    - Outreach Council. Other International Communities. New Zealand (Nambassa Fest), 1980 -1981, 12 items. (Box-folder 18:8)
      Several copies of Waves, a publication by the commune, as well as documents pertaining to their festivals.
    - Outreach Council. Other International Communities. Norway (Holmen Organic Farm), n.d., 14 items. (Box-folder 18:9)
      Photographs of the farm.
    - Outreach Council. Other International Communities. Scotland (Findhorn), 1981-1982; 1985-1988, 14 items. (Box-folder 18:10)
      Miscellaneous brochures for the Findhorn Foundation.
    - Outreach Council. Other International Communities. South American Community/Mexico (Miscellaneous), 1979; 1990, 2 items. (Box-folder 18:11)
      A small and large packet about cellular communication in Nicaragua and South America respectively.
  - K. Planning Council
    - Planning Council. Appendix Charts, 1979 October-1980 January, 134 items. (Box-folder 18:12)
      Charts on budget; notes on other councils.
    - Planning Council. Appendix Charts, 1979 October-1980 January, 100 items. (Box-folder 18:13)
      Charts on budget; notes on other councils; meeting notes/agendas.
    - Planning Council. Community Planning, 1967-1971; 1975, 50 items. (Box-folder 19:1)
    - Planning Council. Community Planning, 1976-1978 May, 101 items. (Box-folder 19:2)
      Weekly notes.
    - Planning Council. Community Planning, 1978 June-1980, 79 items. (Box-folder 19:3)
      Meeting notes; opinion and idea papers.
    - Planning Council. Community Planning, 1982, 32 items. (Box-folder 19:4)
    - Planning Council. Community Planning, 1982, 26 items. (Box-folder 19:5)
    - Planning Council. Community Planning, 1982-1984, 29 items. (Box-folder 19:6)
      Planner informant notes; public meeting notes.
    - Planning Council. Community Planning, 1986-1991, 28 items. (Box-folder 19:7)
    - Planning Council. Community Planning, 1992-1997, 27 items. (Box-folder 19:8)
    - Planning Council. Community Planning. Annual Report by Thomas Jefferson, 1973-1974, 1 item. (Box-folder 20:1)
      Publication regarding public services and health for the Charlottesville, Albermarle, Fluvanna, Greene, and Nelson Counties.
    - Planning Council. Community Planning. East Wind, 1976-1979, 93 items. (Box-folder 20:2)
      Resource planning notes; financial planning notes; project requests.
    - Planning Council. Community Planning. East Wind, 1978-1980, 29 items. (Box-folder 20:3)
      Three-year planning; financial statement.
    - Planning Council. Community Planning, 1974-1975; n.d., 18 items. (Box-folder 20:4)
      Opinion and idea papers.
    - Planning Council. Community Planning, 1980, 65 items. (Box-folder 20:5)
      Opinion and idea papers; planners notes; OS (opinion and idea paper by a member on the donation of a sailboat).
    - Planning Council. Community Planning, 1980, 51 items. (Box-folder 20:6)
      Opinion and idea papers; planner's notes; social planning materials packet; letter to former member.
    - Planning Council. Community Planning, 1981, 52 items. (Box-folder 20:7)
      Opinion and idea papers; planners notes.
    - Planning Council. Community Planning, 1981, 28 items. (Box-folder 20:8)
      Opinion and idea papers; planners notes, meeting notes.
    - Planning Council. Community Planning, 1981-1982, 30 items. (Box-folder 21:1)
      Opinion and idea papers with a guide.
    - Planning Council. Community Planning, 1982, 36 items. (Box-folder 21:2)
    - Planning Council. Community Planning. Policies, 1980-1981, 1 item. (Box-folder 21:3)
      By-laws; Twin Oaks community policy.
    - Planning Council. Community Planning. Survey. Home Is? n.d., 27 items. (Box-folder 21:4)
      Surveys with member responses to the question "What is a home?"
    - Planning Council. Comprehensive Plan and History, 1982-1983; 1990, 28 items. (Box-folder 21:5)
      Timeline of planners; building plan of Twin Oaks.
    - Planning Council. Construction & Utilities Planning. Forestry, 1978, 21:6 (Box-folder 21:6)
      27 items.
      Plans discussing land use and Twin Oaks unit development; sketches illustrating land use; related newspaper article.
    - Planning Council. Construction & Utilities Planning. Glorious Mud, 1976; 1980; 1987, 21:7 (Box-folder 21:7)
      22 items.
      Plans for Glorious Mud, or the Twin Oaks Construction Company, relating to the construction of new housing.
    - Planning Council. Construction & Utilities Planning. Notes, 1978, 117 items. (Box-folder 21:8)
      Notebook; meeting notes; proposals; opinion and idea papers.
    - Planning Council. Economic Planning, 1976, 9 items. (Box-folder 21:9)
      Planners Reports; 1975 income tax return; planning proposals; priorities and trade-off game results wherein all members have an opportunity to prioritize funding and plan the Twin Oaks budget for each year.
    - Planning Council. Economic Planning, 1978, 145 items. (Box-folder 22:1)
      Planners meeting notes.
    - Planning Council. Economic Planning, 1978-1979, 43 items. (Box-folder 22:2)
      Planners Reports; summaries & comments of Economic Plan; balance sheet; securities statement; quota calculations; vacation days and labor exchanges; cuts; planner decisions.
    - Planning Council. Economic Planning, 1978-1983, 42 items. (Box-folder 22:3)
      Money budget reports; budgets by Councils.
    - Planning Council. Economic Planning, 1980-1981, 11 items. (Box-folder 22:4)
      Area worksheets; six month industry review.
    - Planning Council. Economic Planning, 1980-1981, 84 items. (Box-folder 22:5)
      Economic plan for 1981.
    - Planning Council. Economic Planning, 1982, 41 items. (Box-folder 22:6)
      Monthly reviews; proposals; opinion and idea papers; economic plan 1982; farm report.
    - Planning Council. Economic Planning, 1983, 32 items. (Box-folder 22:7)
      Opinion and idea papers; economic plan 1983; reports.
    - Planning Council. Economic Planning, 1984, 48 items. (Box-folder 23:1)
      Three updates of the 1984 Economic Plan Labor and Money Flows with spending projections and totals organized by council.
    - Planning Council. Economic Planning, 1984, 16 items. (Box-folder 23:2)
      Background Information for 1984 Managerial Budgeting organized by Council; planwriting worksheets; six-month review decisions; nine-month review decisions; miscellaneous documents.
    - Planning Council. Economic Planning, 1984, 86 items. (Box-folder 23:3)
      Monthly money budget report with itemized expenditures and remaining funds; letters; opinion and idea papers; balance sheets.
    - Planning Council. Economic Planning, 1984, 60 items. (Box-folder 23:4)
      Monthly money budget report with itemized expenditures and remaining funds; letters; opinion and idea papers; trade-off games; three and six month reviews.
    - Planning Council. Economic Planning, 1985, 28 items. (Box-folder 23:5)
      Balance sheets and other financial data; letters; opinion and idea papers; trade-off games; three and six month reviews.
    - Planning Council. Economic Planning, 1985, 66 items. (Box-folder 23:6)
      Priority requests; opinion and idea papers; council reports.
    - Planning Council. Economic Planning, 1985, 21 items. (Box-folder 23:7)
      Balance sheets; priority plans; three month reviews; financial projections; various economic reports.
    - Planning Council. Economic Planning, 1985, 19 items. (Box-folder 23:8)
      Planwriting worksheets; meeting notes; large economic charts for meetings.
    - Planning Council. Economic Planning, 1985, 6 items. (Box-folder 23:9)
      Information packets for trade-off games; six month reviews; planwriting worksheets.
    - Planning Council. Economic Planning, 1986, 1 item. (Box-folder 24:1)
      Resource proposals; opinion and idea papers; drafted plans; balance sheets; letters; six month reviews.
    - Planning Council. Economic Planning, 1986, 4 items. (Box-folder 24:2)
      1986 Econ Plan/Background Information for 1986 Budget Requests.
    - Planning Council. Economic Planning, 1986, 150 items. (Box-folder 24:3)
      Priority requests for each council and economic area.
    - Planning Council. Economic Planning, 1986, 10 items. (Box-folder 24:4)
      Economic Plan Council Summary Sheets for each council.
    - Planning Council. Economic Planning, 1986, 46 items. (Box-folder 24:5)
      Documents pertaining to the 1986 Trade-off Games where all members have an opportunity to prioritize funding and plan the Twin Oaks budget for each year.
    - Planning Council. Economic Planning, 1986, 100 items. (Box-folder 24:6)
      Planwriting worksheets; six month priority tabulations; labor plans and answer sheets; meeting notes; opinion and idea papers.
    - Planning Council. Economic Planning, 1987, 22 items. (Box-folder 24:7)
      Background information for budget requests; meeting notes; balance sheets; priority presentations; labor reports; letters to, from, and within the planning council.
    - Planning Council. Economic Planning, 1987, 134 items. (Box-folder 24:8)
      Mid-year priority requests; trade-off game.
    - Planning Council. Economic Planning, 1987, 66 items. (Box-folder 25:1)
      Money requests for each council.
    - Planning Council. Economic Planning, 1987, 19 items. (Box-folder 25:2)
      Quarterly economic breakdowns; labor data and requests; labor summary reports; summary sheets.
    - Planning Council. Economic Planning, 1988, 23 items. (Box-folder 25:3)
      Plans for conserving spending in the upcoming year; economic projections; opinion and idea papers; planner meeting notes.
    - Planning Council. Economic Planning, 1988, 60 items. (Box-folder 25:4)
      Planner forums; meeting notes; planning reports; income analyses.
    - Planning Council. Economic Planning, 1988, 68 items. (Box-folder 25:5)
      Economic planning timelines; budget projections and rationales; planwriting sheets; labor data and summaries.
    - Planning Council. Economic Planning, 1988, 30 items. (Box-folder 25:6)
      Ongoing budget sheets and answer sheets.